http://www.self-counsel.com/default/privacy-policy

Privacy Policy
JavaScript seems to be disabled in your browser.
You must have JavaScript enabled in your browser to utilize the functionality of this website.
Self-Counsel Press
Cart
CA$0.00
You have no items in your shopping cart.
Account
Log In
Sign Up
Search:
Digital Content
Greening Your...
Shop
Shop Self Counsel Press:
Digital Content
Greening Your...
Shop
Shop Self Counsel Press:
Privacy Statement for Self-Counsel Press
Self-Counsel Press has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses the information gathering and dissemination practices for this Web site: Self-Counsel Press.
At Self-Counsel Press, we respect our customers’ privacy. We have a long-standing policy of protecting the privacy of our customers in all of our business operations.
That’s why we’ve adopted the CSA Model Code as the basis for our own Self-Counsel Press Privacy Code. It sets out the principles that govern the collection, use and disclosure of our customers’ personal information.
The CSA Model Code also forms the basis for the federal government’s privacy legislation, the “Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act”, which came into effect on January 1, 2001. We’ve set our Self-Counsel Press Privacy Code to ensure that we are in full compliance with this legislation. The result is that we’ve strengthened our commitment to protect our customers’ personal information.
We’ve created this page to inform you about our privacy practices. We want you to understand the purposes for which we collect personal information about our customers. And we want to be sure that we have your consent to continue to collect, use and disclose your personal information for those purposes.
The following is a brief summary of our privacy practices.
Why we collect personal information
If you are a Self-Counsel Press customer, Self-Counsel Press has some basic information about you. We understand that some of this information is private, which is why we collect personal information only for the following purposes:
To establish and maintain a responsible commercial relationship with you and to provide ongoing service. For example, when you buy from us, we collect information that allows us to confirm your identity and credit history so that we can accurately bill and collect for the products and services that you receive from us. We may collect credit card or bank account information, if you prefer the convenience of pre-authorized payment for services.
To understand your needs and preferences. We maintain a record of the products and services you receive from us, and we may ask for additional information so that we can serve you better. For example, we will ask for your e-mail address, so we may confirm your orders electronically.
To develop, enhance, market or provide products and services. For example, we look at how our customers use our products and services, so that we can understand how to improve them. From time to time, we may review and analyze your use of our products and services to help us provide better product recommendations and special offers that we think will interest you.
To manage and develop our business and operations. For example, we analyze customer usage of our websites and facilities to help us manage them efficiently and plan for future growth.
To meet legal and regulatory requirements. For example, we may collect information in response to a court order, or to satisfy a request by the Better Business Bureau or similar body for information about a customer complaint and how it was resolved.
When do we disclose personal information?
There is a variety of circumstances where we may need to disclose some personal information about our customers. Here are some examples:
We may disclose a customer’s personal information to a person who, in the reasonable judgement of Self-Counsel Press, is seeking the information as an agent of the customer. For example, we may provide information about a customer’s account to the customer’s legal representative if we are satisfied that that individual is requesting the information on behalf of the customer.
Customer information may be shared among Self-Counsel Press business units to help us serve our customers better. For example, we maintain warehouse distribution centers in Eastern and Western Canada to facilitate faster delivery to customers and these warehouses share access to the orders data.
We may disclose a customer’s personal information to:
a courier service or delivery company for the efficient and cost-effective delivery of books, forms, kits or other of our products;
a staff member or contractor employed by Self-Counsel Press to supply the customer with forms completion services;
a company or individual employed by Self-Counsel Press to perform functions on its behalf, such as research or data processing; or
an agent used by Self-Counsel Press to evaluate the customer’s credit worthiness or to collect the customer’s account.
Any such disclosure of a customer’s personal information outside of Self-Counsel Press is made on a confidential basis with the information to be used only for the purpose for which it was disclosed.
Subject to applicable regulations, we may disclose a customer’s personal information to a credit reporting agency.
We may disclose a customer’s personal information to a public authority or agent of a public authority, if in the reasonable judgement of Self-Counsel Press, it appears that there is imminent danger to life or property which could be avoided or minimized by disclosure of the information.
In conjunction with special offers or programs, we may disclose customers’ personal information to our program partners, or to third-party agents responsible for administering such offers or programs. Any such disclosure is made on a confidential basis with the customer’s express consent.
How do we protect your personal information?
In order to protect your personal information and your right to privacy, Self-Counsel Press:
will not collect, use or disclose your personal information for any purpose other than those identified above, except with your consent;
will protect your personal information with appropriate security safeguards;
will protect the confidentiality of your personal information when dealing with other companies;
will strive to keep your personal information as accurate and up-to-date as is necessary for the purposes identified above; and
will honour any request you may make for access to your personal information.
What are your choices?
We would like to have your consent to continue to collect, use and disclose your personal information for the purposes identified above. However, we want you to know that you do have choices and can refuse or withdraw your consent as follows:
You may have your name removed from our telephone, mail or e-mail marketing lists. We use these lists to inform you of relevant products, services and special offers that may be of benefit to you.
You may refuse to provide personal information to us. You may also withdraw your consent at any time, subject to legal or contractual restrictions and reasonable notice. However, in either case, this may limit our ability to serve you.
If you have any questions or concerns about our privacy practices, please call us at 1-800-663-3007, 8:30 a.m. - 5:00 p.m. P.S.T., Monday through Friday. Alternatively, you may send an email message to privacy@self-counsel.com and we will respond. Otherwise, we will assume that we have your consent to continue to collect, use and disclose your personal information for the purposes identified above.
The small print
On this site, the words “we” or “Self-Counsel Press” refer to Self-Counsel Press Limited and its subsidiary companies, as they may exist from time to time. These include, without limitation, the subsidiaries which carry on business under the following names: Self-Counsel Press and Self-Counsel Press Inc. The words “we” and “Self-Counsel Press” do not include independent dealers and distributors of Self-Counsel Press products and services.
The Self-Counsel Press Privacy Code does not limit the collection, use or disclosure by Self-Counsel Press of information that is publicly available. This includes: (a) a customer’s name, address, telephone number, and e-mail address, when listed in a directory or available through directory assistance; and (b) other information about the customer that is publicly available and is specified by regulation pursuant to the “Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act.”
The Self-Counsel Press Privacy Code does not apply to information regarding Self-Counsel Press corporate customers. However, such information is protected by other Self-Counsel Press policies and practices and through contractual arrangements.
The Self-Counsel Press Privacy Code and the privacy practices described in this site are subject to the provisions of all applicable legislation and regulations.
We can be contacted at:
Contact Us by email.
About Self-Counsel Press
Self-Counsel Press is the premier source for do-it-yourself law and small business books.
Our books, e- books, and form kits are designed to help you help yourself.
Divorce Typing Service (BC only)
Find our books at these and other fine retailers:
independent bookstore (ABA)
© 2017 Self-Counsel Press. All Rights Reserved.
Site built by CloudQuarry LLC
To top
